## **CURRICULUM VITAE**

### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Name: Stuart Middleton

Position: Freelance SQS/MQS/CM

Address: Derby

Salary: £340 - 370/day

Notice: 4 weeks

**EDUCATION** 

Sheffield Hallam University BSC (Hons) Quantity Surveying

#### **PROFILE**

Stuart is self motivated, enthusiastic individual with a keen interest in design and construction. He has been working within the construction industry since August 2000 and has progressed from trainee QS right through to Commercial Manager. He has completed small contracts from 100k right through to £20m schemes and has run accounts in excess of £40m from a commercial management role for major international contractors.

Having successfully been sponsored for my Surveying Degree through a member of the major contractors group, during his 15 years in the industry he has gained enviable experience leading on multi million pound projects for prestigious clients. He has progressed through various grades within his career demonstrating that he is continuously increasing his knowledge and skills in the industry striving for self-improvement.

Stuart has excellent interpersonal skills enabling him to be a key part of any project, leading on project discussions, negotiations and performance matters. His management and analytical skills allow him to manage multiple projects and budgets ensuring cost control and efficiency. He is experienced in working on various forms of contracts including JCT contracts, Design and Build single stage and two stage contracts and NEC contracts. An asset to any team he is an exceptional team player focusing on the overall team and organizational objectives.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

October 2018 – Present WINVIC CONSTRUCTION LTD

Position: Senior Quantity Surveyor

Stuart is currently working with Winvic Construction on the distribution hub at East Midlands Gateway. Works consist of general QS duties on a £45m scheme whilst assisting the younger members of the team where required

Sep 2015 – August 2018 DSP CONSTRUCTION MANAGEMENT

Position: Freelance Commercial Lead

Engaged by DSP Construction Management as a Managing Surveyor responsible for overseeing The Aldi Head Office Development in Atherstone. The scheme entails the construction of a 450 space MSCP - £7m, a 20,000 ft2 mezzanine - £3m, two new office developments, £20m each and the refurbishment of the current office space along with reconfiguration of the warehosue

Apr 2012 – Mar 2015 ISG PLC

Position: Commercial Manager

Stuart joined ISG retail as a Commercial Manager employed to oversee the commercial function on the ASDA account. Working in new build, remodels, acquisitions extensions and small works sectors on an account worth in excess of £45 million pounds per annum. Highlight schemes during this time were the tendering and securing of the acquisition and remodel framework along with the delivery of over 250,000 ft2 of new retail space for ASDA.

#### **Duties:**

- Responsibility and accountability for the Commercial team and Contractual matters on the £45m ASDA Framework Account
- Ensuring cash maximisation and risk reduction across all projects in all work streams
- Maximise margins across the account whilst growing turnover in line with the business plan
- Client management throughout all processes including commercial/operational and other key stakeholders
- Management of a team of 12 surveyors working in new build, extensions, fitout, developer shells, acquisitions, remodels, PFS ranging from 50k to £19m Key Achievements
- Delivery of over 250,000 ft2 of new retail Space
- Tendering and Securing the acquisition and remodel frameworks.

Jan 2011 – Apr 2012 BASEBUILD SERVICES
Position: Senior Quantity Surveyor

In January 2011 Stuart was employed as a Commercial Manager for Basebuild Services to head up the commercial team on the Sainsburys framework account. The primary function of his role was to develop and nurture existing relationships with the client whilst delivering high quality schemes for less than budget whilst maximizing profit and reducing our commercial risk across the schemes, this is inclusive of all aspects of the commercial role from inception right through to final account agreements.

In the previous 12 months he commercially managed and delivered some £22 million pounds worth of turnover for Basebuild spread across 4 schemes, these being two extensions, 1 acquisition and 1 remodel to successful outcome not only for Basebuild but also the client.

Jan 2008 – Jan 2011

**MCLAREN CONSTRUCTION** 

Position:

Senior Quantity Surveyor

In 2007 Stuart was offered the opportunity to join McLaren Construction as a Senior Surveyor. Within his time spent at McLaren he has completed several new builds in the retail sector. He has also completed commercial offices and two new MSCP constructions for NCP.

He also was involved with the development of the McLaren business out in the United Arab Emirates and played a part in negotiating and securing the first contract for McLaren out in Dubai. This is the construction of large distribution centre on the outskirts of Dubai and is a pivotal business move for McLaren.

Jan 2010 – Oct 2010:

He has been heavily involved with the development of the Retail sector for McLaren Construction. He has completed two number retail remodels for ASDA and am currently negotiating cost plans with ASDA for numerous schemes in the UK.

He has also been asked to head up the development of the Morrisons account and is currently developing the cost plans for two schemes in the UK that commence and complete in 2011.

Jan 2009 – Jan 2010:

Two number Multi Storey Car Park Project Value - £18 million Programme – 54 weeks Client – National Car Parks

Mar 2008 - Sep 2008:

Construction of two industrial units, Birmingham Project Value - £4 million Programme – 28 weeks Client – St Modwen

Jan 2008 - Dec 2008:

New build office development, Leicester Project Value - £12 million Programme – 48 weeks Client – Gazeley

May 2005 – Jan 2008
Career Progression:
BOWMER & KIRKLAND
Senior Quantity Surveyor
Quantity Surveyor

During May 2005 an opportunity arose to join, Bowmer & Kirkland Ltd as part of their retail based team. My previous experience of retail work for Tesco enabled me to be exposed to the other retailers in this sector, namely Sainsbury, ASDA and Marks and Spencer.

During my period of employment with Bowmer & Kirkland I was involved in numerous schemes that ranged from new builds, refits, extensions, fit outs and mixed use developments, that were diverse in both their complexity, costs and geographic locations.

He was involved with many of these schemes from inception through to completion which included both project estimation and final account agreements.

Below is a brief summary of the schemes I undertook during my employment with B & K.

Jul 2007 - Jan 2008:

Part completion of an inner town redevelopment of a shopping centre with associated multi story car park. He ran the scheme as a project SQS and reported directly to the relevant commercial manager.

Project Value - £18.5 million Programme – 88 weeks Client – Vale Retail/ASDA

Dec 2006 - Jul 2007:

Worked a SQS on a 40,000 sqft timber frame new build supermarket in Shaw, Oldham. He was the project SQS for the scheme and as such was responsible for all aspects of the commercial function. Project Value - £10 million

Programme – 25 weeks

Client – ASDA

Sep 2006 - Nov 2006:

Completion of an acquisition store fit out in Pocklington, York. The scheme was a 20,000 sqft strip out and fit out to bring the store up to current standards. He was responsible for the scheme from conception to delivery.

Project Value - £2.1 million Programme – 8 weeks Client – Sainsbury's

Dec 2006 - Jul 2007:

Worked a SQS on a 40,000 sq ft timber frame new build supermarket in Shaw, Oldham. He was the project SQS for the scheme and as such was responsible for all aspects of the commercial function. Project Value - £10 million

Programme – 25 weeks

Client – ASDA

Jul 2007 - Jan 2008:

Part completion of an inner town redevelopment of a shopping centre with associated multi story car park. He ran the scheme as a project SQS and reported directly to the relevant commercial manager.

Project Value - £18.5 million Programme – 88 weeks Client – Vale Retail/ASDA

Aug 2000 – May 2005TAYLOR WOODROWCareer Progression:Quantity Surveyor

# **Assistant Quantity Surveyor**

During his time with Taylor Woodrow, Stuart undertook and completed numerous schemes. The first project he was involved with was a PFI scheme for the Ministry Of Defence; this included the construction of a new Barracks at their site in Melton Mowbray.

After completion of the above scheme he was immediately transferred to Taylor Woodrow's retail sector of the business. He worked within this sector for four years where he undertook and completed 6 schemes with values ranging between £6 million and £16 million pounds for their blue chip client Tesco. These schemes included the first flag ship 'store on stilts' within the UK which was constructed in Altrincham, successful completion of this scheme enabled Taylor Woodrow to complete a further two similar schemes in Burnley and Long Eaton.

His exposure to this client and sector not only enabled me to undertake new build constructions but also refits, extensions and mixed use developments.

Below is a brief summary of the schemes he was involved with and the changes to my roles and responsibilities during my employment with Taylor Woodrow.

Jun 2004 - Feb 2005:

Worked as a QS under the control of a senior QS on a 75,000 sq. ft. new build store on stilts supermarket in Long Eaton on behalf of Tesco. He managed all sub-contractors and was responsible for procurement and elements of the final accounts.

Project Value - £16 million Programme – 36 weeks Client - Tesco

Jan 2004 – Jun 2004:

Worked as a QS on a retail extension on behalf of Tesco. The scheme was an extension to three sides of the existing store with associated works to the car park. He was responsible for all elements of a commercial nature.

Project Value - £7 million Programme – 24 weeks Client – Tesco

Jun 2003 - Nov 2003:

Whilst working for Taylor Woodrow Stuart was asked to take over a scheme in Nottingham due to the insolvency of the original main contractor, the staff were taken on from Taylor Woodrow and he was asked to run the scheme. The scheme was a multi-story domestic project with basement commercial unit in the centre of Nottingham. He was responsible for all commercial functions.

Project Value - £6 million Programme – 24 weeks Client – Unknown

Dec 2002 – May 2003:

Worked as an Assistant QS on Tesco Burnley, the second store on stilts to be built in the UK. He was responsible for all procurement, valuations, sub contract management including variations, cost reporting and application for payment.

Project Value - £17 million Programme – 24 weeks (during my involvement) Client – Tesco

Jan 2002 - Nov 2002:

Worked as an Assistant QS on Tesco Altrincham, the first supermarket in the UK to be built on 'stilts'. He was responsible for procurement, valuation and payment of sub-contractor application, remeasurement and had a small input into the management of variations.

Project Value - £15 million Programme – 44 weeks Client – Tesco

Aug 2000 – Jan 2002:

Worked as an Assistant QS in a commercial team of three on a PFI MOD Barracks. He was responsible for small elements of procurement, material management and re-measures. Project Value - £14 million

Programme – 24 weeks Client – MOD